<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Humble petition of the common people of England, to the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament, particularly to their representatives, the House of Commons</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 27KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A45017</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12086638</idno>
  <idno type="VID">53760</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240953015</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing H3494</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R5784</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12086638</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A45017)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 53760)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 73:20)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Humble petition of the common people of England, to the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament, particularly to their representatives, the House of Commons</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Against the land tax of four shillings in the pound.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Yale University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Land value taxation --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:53760:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:53760:1"/>
            <head>The Humble PETITION of the Common People of <hi>England,</hi> to the Lords and Commons Assembled in Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, Particularly to their Representatives the House of Commons:</head>
            <opener>Humbly Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>THAT whereas we conceive You laid this Tax of Four Shillings in the Pound upon Landed Men, to ease those of the poorer Sort, we are justly apprehensive that though this Imposition does light immediately upon them, yet it will fall at the next Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move most heavy upon <hi>Ʋs:</hi> For those being generally the richest Men in the Nation, who disperse their Money by employing all sorts of Workmen, and Artificers, and by laying it out in <hi>Shops;</hi> (which are the only Liveli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hoods of the generality of the meaner Subjects;) They will, when they become thus straitned, lay out very little, and many of them none at all, to set us to work in our several Trades, or to buy our Commodities: By which Means, having no other ways of Subsistence, we shall not be able to maintain our Families, keep open our Shops, nor, by consequence, to live.</p>
            <p>And this Apprehension of Ours is aggravated by this Consideration, That 'tis too well known that very many of that sort of Richer Men, through the <hi>S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>y</hi> of <hi>Money,</hi> and <hi>Dam<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of <hi>Trade,</hi> which occasion the Indigency of the <hi>Tenants,</hi> do scarce receive half their Rents, and some not a quarter of them; and yet they are taxed for their whole Years Revenue, though their <hi>Incomes</hi> be never so small: Whence, being scarce able to buy what is precisely necessary for their <hi>Food, Raiment,</hi> and <hi>Lodging,</hi> they will not think fit to lay out one Penny of Money in any <hi>Superfluities,</hi> or less ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessary Commodities, (by which notwithstanding, and only which, in <hi>making,</hi> and <hi>vending</hi> them, half of us do live;) it will necessarily follow, that not only all those <hi>Artificers,</hi> and <hi>Shopkeepers,</hi> will be utterly <hi>undone;</hi> but that Multitudes also of the poorest sort, who do now live meerly by their <hi>voluntary Charity,</hi> and <hi>Benevolence,</hi> will inevitably perish. We do therefore humbly recommend it to Your Wisdoms to find out some effica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious Means to supply these Wants, and avert from the <hi>People</hi> such <hi>ruinous</hi> Mischiefs, which we foresee, and in part experience already, are coming upon us, and likely to over whelm us.</p>
            <p>As for all those, who (we meddle not upon what Principle) shall refuse the <hi>Oaths,</hi> and are by this <hi>Act</hi> obliged to pay eight Shillings in the Pound; we look upon them as on so many ruined Men, whence we cannot expect one Penny of gain from them, either by their employing us, or by their buying our <hi>Wares:</hi> And how many those may be we do not know, only we
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:53760:2"/> are sure that all is lost to us which we might otherwise expect to get from them.</p>
            <p>Also, since many even of the richer sort of Subjects, do, upon the Pros<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pect of this <hi>Cruel Tax,</hi> already cast about to leave off House-keeping, put away Servants, live in a Room or two, and Board themselves, seeing other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise no possibility of subsisting: We do humbly beg of your Wisdoms to contrive some way how these discarded Servants may live, in regard they have no other way to do it but by their serving, nor will any in those Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumstances think fit to entertain more Servants than they had before; whence, unless some laudable Course be taken for them to subsist, 'tis to be feared that the Men-Servants, rather than starve, will turn Rogues, and fill the High-ways with Robbers, chusing rather to hazard Hanging in their own Countrey, than to Fight for the <hi>Confederates</hi> in <hi>Flanders,</hi> where our <hi>English</hi> Soldiers have been so basely used, by starving, or dying of Diseases in their bad Quarters, or knockt on the Head by those they came to <hi>defend,</hi> or else by being exposed to be massacred by the <hi>French,</hi> while the <hi>Confede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rates</hi> look on, and refuse to assist or relieve them: And as for the <hi>Maid-Servants,</hi> 'tis to be feared, lest, being thus abandoned, they will, rather than beg or starve, be easily tempted to Lewdness; which must tend in a high measure to the debauching some considerable part of the Nation. We do also humbly conceive, that 'tis a matter worthy your Consideration how those Houses that stand empty when the Gentrey are gone to Lodgings can enable the Owners (many of which have nothing else to live on) to pay such excessive Taxes for them, when they make not the least benefit of them, and have no Estate else to pay them with, nor you to live themselves. And the Case of the Shop-keepers will be no less deplorable, who must pay Four Shillings in Twenty for the worth of their Shop-Goods; and yet must lose, by the straitning the richer sort, as is above-said, far the better half of their Customers, who, by buying them, should furnish them with Money to pay those Taxes, and maintain their Families.</p>
            <p>Nor do we doubt but you will think it becomes the Wisdom of the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament to take some way to pay the <hi>Bankers</hi> the <hi>Exchequer Money</hi> so long due, at least the Interest of it so far behind: The neglect of which, though it be confest that 'tis most legally due, detains many Thousands in a starv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Condition. As also to find some Expedient to relieve the Families of the <hi>Merchants,</hi> and <hi>Ensurers,</hi> who are already Bankrupt; and those many others, who will e're long be in the same Condition, by the loss of their <hi>Ships</hi> and <hi>Goods</hi> at Sea, during the time of this War; the <hi>Wealth, Honour,</hi> and <hi>Trade</hi> of the Nation, and particularly of the <hi>City</hi> of <hi>London,</hi> so much depending on the Sufficiency and Credit of the Merchants. And lastly, that the Loss which Thousands do receive by <hi>His Majesty's</hi> Debts for Stores, and upon many other Accounts, amounting to not a <hi>few Millions,</hi> be some way supplied. All which, setting aside these <hi>Cruel Taxes,</hi> and such heavy Burthens to the Subject, that it cannot but be thought worthy the high <hi>Senate</hi>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:53760:2"/> of Parliament to consider them, and to take them off the Backs of the People, who are now no longer able to support them.</p>
            <p>Lastly, we do humbly implore your best Care, as well for your own sakes as ours, that you would take it into your most serious Consideration what will become of the Nation if these <hi>Taxes</hi> proceed, and continue; which, to our extream Grief, your Carriage lets us see you are resolv'd shall. No wise Man, who knows how things stand between the <hi>French King</hi> and the <hi>Confederates,</hi> and how he every Year gains upon them, can think the War is more likely to have an end, than it was the first or second Year as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter it began. And how shall <hi>England,</hi> so exhausted of Money, and impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verished by <hi>excessive Taxes,</hi> and want of Trade, be able to support it? Your selves are sensible what great Difficulties you meet with to raise Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney enough for this present <hi>Campaign:</hi> What insuperable Difficulties must you then find to raise what is sufficient for the next, and the next to that, and so forwards? <hi>Fore-seeing</hi> and <hi>Fore-casting</hi> are the best Acts of <hi>Prudence,</hi> and most necessary for Persons in your Station. All Histories inform us how impossible it is to expect that the People will tamely sit still, when they see themselves half ruin'd already, and likely to be so <hi>totally;</hi> and the experi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence of the <hi>Meb</hi> at <hi>Rotterdam,</hi> though they be in a better Condition than we, confirms it, who threaten their Magistrates in a mutinous manner, unless they have either <hi>Peace,</hi> or <hi>Trade,</hi> with <hi>Fance,</hi> What then can the Conse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence of this be here, but Heart-burnings against the Government, which instead of promoting the <hi>Common Good,</hi> destroys it, and instead of securing to them Peace, and Plenty, has engaged them in an endless War, and beggars them to maintain it? What can be expected but that the generality of the Complainers, who begin to speak loud enough in many places already, growing at length universally acquainted with the thoughts of the rest, will thence take courage to break out into open <hi>Rebellion?</hi> The <hi>Poor,</hi> en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forced by their Necessities, will fall to plunder the <hi>Rich,</hi> and most certainly fall upon your Selves in the first place, looking upon you as on Men <hi>umrue</hi> to the <hi>Trust</hi> the Countrey has reposed in you, and impowered you with; and apprehending that instead of being their Protectors, against the Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pressions of the <hi>Court-Party,</hi> you are indeed their greatest Undoers, and the only Men who have brought them to all this Misery. To which will help forward, and encrease their hatred against you, the Conceit already spread far and near throughout the Nation, That the greatest part of you are <hi>Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners,</hi> and that you over-vote the true <hi>Patriots</hi> for your Money; and so are the sole Cause of these intolerable Grievances of the People. 'Tis easy then to conceive what a barbarous Treaty you are like to receiver from their rude Natures so highly exasperated, while they look upon you as <hi>Mercenary Hirelings</hi> of the <hi>Court,</hi> who sacrifice the <hi>Common Good</hi> to your own <hi>Private Interest,</hi> and <hi>sell</hi> the People for your <hi>own Lucre.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Your Wisdoms cannot but see how much it will concern your Honour, and perhaps your Safety too, to take off, by your Actions, e're you rise,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:53760:3"/> this Scandal of being <hi>Pensioners</hi> to the Court, and selling the Money of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> that you may share in the spoil. And that you may be able to satisfie the Nation, 'tis our Duty to represent to you what is said of you; and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>at occasion 'tis conceived you have given for such a grievous Imputation. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> is alledged that you have scarce past one Vote thorowly for any thing that <hi>eases</hi> or <hi>benefits</hi> the People; but that in a manner all your Endeavours, excepting particular Bills, have been employed to invent new ways how to <hi>Tax</hi> and <hi>Burthen</hi> them all that is possible. Nay, that you have <hi>wav'd</hi> or <hi>thrown</hi> out every Bill that was not grateful to the Court, though it never so much concerned the Subjects Good, as, <hi>the Regulating Tryals in Cases of High-Treason, That no more of our Money be Transported out of</hi> England, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Nay, that though it were offered to supply our Soldiers in <hi>Flanders</hi> with Pay, without either transporting our Money thither in <hi>Specie,</hi> or by Bills of Exchange, or by sending our <hi>Corn</hi> or <hi>Flesh</hi> thither to starve the People this dear Year, yet to the great Wonder of all indifferent Men it was not accepted of; which could bear no other Construction, but that the Court liked it not, because it was against the Interest of the <hi>Dutch,</hi> who have made and do still make such a vast gain by our English Money. Also that the Petition of bringing in <hi>Ʋnthrown Silk</hi> over Land, did not only suffer a Rejection but a <hi>Reprimand,</hi> though highly beneficial to the Weavers, and by consequence to the Nation, by lessening the dearness of it; because four or five of your Members, who monopolize that Trade, and bring it by Sea, were against it. Lastly, we wonder when that happy day will come that the relief of the <hi>Poor Orphans</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> so often talk'd of in your Votes these two years, and more, will effectually be taken into Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sideration.</p>
            <p>They complain too of your backwardness to <hi>advise</hi> the King, though he has given you fair occasion to do it; and you may find Abuses enough, or rather you know them well enough already, to represent to him, the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dress of which would exceedingly please the Nation, were you not affraid that the advising a Reformation would displease the Court. As, that the <hi>Dutch</hi> Counsellors be removed, all <hi>England</hi> being sensible that that crafty and interested Nation, being our only Competitors in Trade, nothing can be more pernicious to the Interest of <hi>England</hi> than the Influence they have upon the King, and consequently the greatest part of the <hi>Court,</hi> and, 'tis seared, on your selves too, by your espousing the <hi>Court-Interest;</hi> which to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether with the Aversion they all have to our Nation, makes them odious to our Countreymen, in Camp, City, and Countrey, nay to many even in the Court too. Also, That the Seamen have their full Pay, sufficient Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney having been raised to pay them: That our Soldiers in <hi>Flanders</hi> be better Pay'd, better Quarter'd, and not so barbarously used as they have been: Things being still carried so as if the <hi>English</hi> were the very Scum and Rubbish of all Nations. That in Fights at Land the <hi>Dutch</hi> may be engaged as well as the <hi>English,</hi> nor permitted to stand still, and to their great content look
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:53760:3"/> on, while our Countreymen are knock'd o'th' Head. That the Nation have an Account why, or how the <hi>Descent,</hi> for which they paid so dear, came to miscarry; and what is become of the Arms, Ammunition, and Ord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance carried out of the <hi>Tower</hi> of <hi>London</hi> to make that <hi>Descent,</hi> and that, when that occasion is over, it be brought back thither; lest all our Arms, after a while, come to be transported as well as our Money, which has an ill signification, and may be apt to create Fears, lest the Project of <hi>Conquest</hi> be still carrying on, though the two Books be burnt. That an Account be given how it happens that Money was raised for 28000 Soldiers to make the <hi>Descent,</hi> yet but 12000 went; and what is become of the over-plus Money? That it be look'd narrowly into, who fetch'd the Infamous Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lain <hi>Young,</hi> and his Companion out of <hi>Newgate,</hi> furnished their Backs with new Cloaths, and filled their Pockets with Money; and why they could not be prosecuted till towards the sitting of the Parliament? For if such things as these be stifled, and the Greet Men behind the Curtain be left undiscove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, our very Lives are not safe against such Contrivances, much less the Life of any true Patriot against the Court. That our Money be no more Transported, nor our Corn and Flesh this dear Year: Against which Abuses though you made no Provision, yet it has much disgusted the People, that in several Places they have mutinied upon it; foreseeing that the <hi>Dutch</hi> will buy up our Corn, and after <hi>Midsummer,</hi> when we are half famished, bring it back; and, as is their Trick, sell it to us again twice as dear. Lastly, it seems fitting you should advise the King that the Money you gave to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide Stores should be paid to the Providers of them; for it's certain they begin already to baulk and defraud them afresh, refusing to pay them for what they have brought in, unless they bring in more which they intend shall be left unpaid.</p>
            <p>Again it is alledged, that though you sit there to see the Laws of the Land suffer no Detriment, and though you cannot but know how frequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, openly, and erroneously divers, and even many of them are broken; yet, contrary to the manner of your Predecessors, you suffer it unconcern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>edly; and seem to approve the breaking them by your <hi>silence,</hi> and conni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance. You have seen the Subjects, even the Nobility, nay Peers of the Realm, clapt up in Prison, and put in the <hi>Tower</hi> by Illegal Warrants from my Lord <hi>Nottingham,</hi> without any Evidence brought against them, then or since; than which nothing could be more directly against the Liberty of the Subject; and yet, though it were highly complained of by the Persons ag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grieved, you shewed no Resentment against the Violater of that Fundamen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal Law, nor ordered any Satisfaction to be made to those who were inju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red; but instead of that, Pardons are given to the Infringers of the Law, to encourage the Courtiers to do the same for the future. Again, whereas formerly, when any Man was Press'd, he had permission to send for his Friends, that so the Captain might have Information whether the Quality of the Person, or his Circumstances, ought to exempt him: Now the People
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:53760:4"/> of all sorts are Spirited away, and clapt on Ship-board, their Friends not knowing what is become of them; and amongst the rest many married Men, and Housholders, are barbarously seized, and hurryed on Board without having the Liberty to take a sad Farewel of their Wives and Children; who, living only by their Labour, are left to starve: And which makes it yet more lawless, they are Press'd pretendedly for Sea-Service, but most part of them are prest by the Money of our Captains come out of <hi>Flanders,</hi> to serve under them at Land, directly against our <hi>English</hi> Laws, forbidding that any should be prest for <hi>Land-Service;</hi> and so, as they was last Year, they are carried from Ship-board into <hi>Flanders</hi> whether they will or no; not only to serve at Land in a Foreign Country, but to sight too for the Interest of Foreigners, where they shall be badly paid, and used like Dogs by the very Persons they come to defend. Indeed, you gave order that a Servant of one of your <hi>Members</hi> should be sought after, and brought back: But since you see by that, that they force away any Subject without making any di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stinction; Why was there not an Order made to regulate the <hi>Pressing,</hi> and restraining <hi>Press-Masters</hi> from such licentious Villainies, and treating the Free-born <hi>English</hi> as if they were so many Slaves; since the Liberty of every <hi>English</hi> Subject ought to be as dear to you as that of one of your own Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants; and <hi>Magna Charta,</hi> securing the Liberty of the Subject, ought to be as Sacred in your Esteem as is the Priviledge of a Servant belonging to a <hi>Member</hi> of the <hi>House</hi> of <hi>Commons?</hi> Indeed, when the Deed is done, and the <hi>Pressing</hi> over, we have the comfort to be told in a <hi>Gazette,</hi> that the King approves not such doings, which we will believe when we have all those who were <hi>illegally</hi> Prest sent back. But how much more worthy your Care had it been to prevent, and resent it while it was doing; especially since the same Usage, and the same Complaint was made last Year? It must be confest too, that you may reflect in time what blackest Infamy it will lay upon your selves at present, and on your Posterity hereafter; when it can with Truth be said now, and will be recorded in History, that these two Parliaments in four Years gave away, to fight for Foreigners, (and those our greatest Enemies) six or seven and twenty Millions of <hi>English</hi> Money, though the Subject were damnified one way or other ten Millions besides: That they suffered great part of this Money to be transported; the Laws of the Land to be frequently broken; the <hi>English</hi> Subjects to be grinded, abused, impoverished, and enslaved; The Trade and Interest of a Foreign Nation, our worst Enemy, to be promoted, to the highest Prejudice of the <hi>Trade</hi> and <hi>Interest</hi> of <hi>England:</hi> And yet either out of <hi>slavish Fear,</hi> or <hi>for did Lucre,</hi> they wanted the Courage, or the Honesty, to stand up for the People; no not even for their own Liberty, or Priviledges; but put both their own Necks, and the Necks of the Nation, under the Feet of a <hi>Foreign Prince,</hi> and made it their chief Business to <hi>ruine</hi> their Countrey. These kind of Actions make us see that we are in effect treated according to the Law of <hi>Conquest,</hi> though they will not name it: And that we are indeed
<pb facs="tcp:53760:4"/>
               <hi>Slaves</hi> to the Court, and that the worst of <hi>Slaves;</hi> nay, in some regard worse than those under the <hi>Turk;</hi> for they frequently find Redemption, but we can have no hopes any can redeem us, since your selves who only can, and ought to do it, out of fear of the Court, do by your Connivance refuse us that Duty, and allow our Slavery.</p>
            <p>Many other Laws your Wisdoms may discover, that without any Scruple or Contradiction are broken at the Arbitrary Pleasure of the <hi>Coint,</hi> which it may become your Wisdoms to enquire into, and see amended. In the mean time, we humbly beg Pardon if we be highly concerned to see seven or eight and twenty Millions given, by your Votes, out of the Purse of the Nation in less than five Years, more than has been raised by all the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments put together this hundred and forty Years, (and some Millions more lost to us by the Merchants Ships taken by the <hi>French;</hi>) and yet scarce any Body paid but Foreigners; and after all this vast Expence, nothing has been done with it, but it's all thrown away to no purpose, our Enemies dayly gaining ground upon us: Which obliges us to petition you for this Satisfaction, That you will please to acquaint the Nation how long you in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to continue these cruel Impositions; that we may at once know our Doom. This unparallel'd Grievance is alone beyond our Strength to sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port; but when the Violation of our Laws and Liberties breaks in upon us too, we hope you will easily allow our Excuse, if with all humbly Candour we expose our sad Condition, complain sensibly of it, and implore your Relief: Which we had much rather wish by your means, than that over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strain'd Nature, not able to contain it self any longer, and acting upon the Principle of <hi>Self-Preservation</hi> from Starving, and Slavery, should be oblig'd by lawless Necessity to seek its own Redress, and force its way to its own Freedom, and the securing its own Livelihood, and Life.</p>
            <p>You know that far less Grievances than those we already feel, (not to speak of those many more we are like to suffer, compared to which the Ship-Money, which bread such Combustions, was but a Flea biting;) have formerly incited Parliaments (jealous of the wronging the Common Good) to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>inst, dethrone, and even barbarously to put to death their <hi>Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Hereditary King,</hi> and to <hi>Abdicate King James,</hi> though what we suffered under him, who never required any Taxes of us at all, was far short of our present Pressures. We are far from wishing to transport you into any such extravagant Resentments: Only it amuses every one to see you, our Patriots and Guardians, seem altogether insensible of our present Hardships, and impending Ruine; but that regardless of us you drive on suriously when the Court commands, though you run us, your selves, and the whole Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion into unavoidable and irrecoverable Precipices.</p>
            <p>The Summ of our present most Humble Petition is this, That you would please, by your contrary Proceedings, to take Order that the Scandal of a very great part of the Nation may be remov'd, and the Aspersion wip'd off <hi>that the Court carries and sweeps all before it,</hi> both Money, Laws, property,
<pb facs="tcp:53760:5"/> and Liberty of the Subject, Interest of the Nation, and even the Parliament it self; and that through your Connivance, and Co-operation, they have left us nothing safe, from being sacrificed to them, but our <hi>Religion,</hi> a thing which they are not over-fond of themselves. Whence the People begin to apprehend that they are under a state of an <hi>Arbitrary Power</hi> already; not under a King alone, for that might receive some check from a Parliament standing up stifly for our Laws, but (which is incomparably worse) under the Monarchical, Aristocratical, and Democratical parts of our Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; that is, by King, Lords, and House of Commons conspiring to <hi>Their Ruine.</hi> Of which Three, notwithstanding, only the Monarch is Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>solute, and Unlimited, not by our National Constitution, but by the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect complying and subserviency of the other Two to the <hi>Court-Party;</hi> and their giving up, and resolving the Power they have into the Other: Which yet we would hope from your burning the two Books, designed by the <hi>Court</hi> to set up the Title of <hi>Conquest,</hi> you do not seeingly, and purposely intend; but that you are insensibly led on by a kind of Complacency for the <hi>Court</hi> to admit its Equivalent: While in all Things, and on all Occasions, (your selves best know upon what Motive) you second and submit to the <hi>Will</hi> and <hi>Pleasure</hi> of the Supream Magistrate, and He to the <hi>Advice</hi> of <hi>Dutch Counsellors, England</hi>'s <hi>Greatest</hi> and <hi>Subtilest Enemies.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>We shall dayly pray that the Great Giver of all True Wisdom, may inspire You with such Counsels, as may give this poor Kingdom occasion to Love and Magnify You as Their best Friends, Their Easers and Deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verers; and not to repine at You, and hate You, as the Betrayers of Your Trust, Their G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ess Enemies, and most Cruel Oppressors.</closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="notice">
            <head>ADVERTISEMENT.</head>
            <p>WHereas the Author of the <hi>Remarks upon the present Confederacy, &amp;c.</hi> has, <hi>pag.</hi> 22. a Passage reflecting on the Reputation of Lieutenant Gen. <hi>Hamilton,</hi> which he took from a general Report, which he had not then heard contradicted; the Author is since informed that the said Report was a Mistake and Calumny, and the Lieutenant a Person of Integrity, and to this Day in his Majesty's Favour: He desires this may be taken notice of, hoping it may be a Means to clear his Reputation from so scandalous and false a Report so universally spread.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:53760:5"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>